A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Program Management, Office Files of Kyle Reis FA1453
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Office of Program Management, Office Files of Kyle Reis
1994-2007
Rockefeller Archive Center
Reis, Kyle C.
Ford Foundation
FA1453
1.14 Cubic Feet 3 LTR size Hollinger boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necesary.
This material was transferred to RAC in 2018 by the Ford Foundation and was ingested by the RAC as Accessions 2018:035.
Biographical / Historical
The Ford Foundation was chartered by Henry and Edsel Ford in 1936 "to receive and administer funds for scientific, educational and charitable purposes, all for the public welfare", and initially served the Ford family's charitable interests in the Detroit area. Following the deaths of Edsel Ford (1943) and Henry Ford (1947), the Foundation was propelled to the forefront of philanthropy as the largest American foundation in terms of both endowment and yearly expenditures, and with an international scope to its major program areas.
During the Foundation's first twenty years its major programs were in international economic development, primary and higher education, educational and public broadcasting, behavioral sciences, civil liberties, urban development, fine arts and the humanities. The Ford Foundation also partnered with the Rockefeller Foundation in supporting agricultural development in South America, Africa, and Southeast Asia. Since the 1970s, the Foundation has also pioneered programs in women's rights, energy policy, micro-financing in under-developed countries, establishing human rights groups, and improving international HIV/AIDS education.
Arrangement
Collections consists of only one series.
Original order was maintained during processing
The collection arrangement is as follows:
Series 1. Office files, 1994-2007
Biographical / Historical
Kyle Reis worked at the Ford Foundation from 1987-2013. He began as an Archives Assistant and then took on a number of different positions related to grants management and operations. In 2009, he became Manager of Strategy and Operations and served in that position until he left the foundation in 2013.
He continued his career in philanthropy after his time at Ford by becoming Senior Director and East Coast Representative for TechSoup, an international network of NGOs that provides technical services to other NGOs.
Other Finding Aids
Finding aids concerning the office files of other Ford Foundation officers in the Office of Program Management and Office of Management Services include:
FA685 Ford Foundation records, Office of Program Management, Program Operations and Services, Assets Division, Office Files of Fred Tom
FA652 Ford Foundation records, Office of Management Services, Office Files of Steven Lawry
Scope and Contents
Collection holds the office files of Ford Foundation staff member Kyle Reis. The files were created during Reis' time at Ford's Office of Management Services and Office of Program Management. Documents within the collection suggest that the Office of Management Services became the Office of Program Management around the year 2006. The timeframe within which the records were created encompasses Reis's positions as Field Office Liaison and Regional Grants Manager for the Africa Program (1994-1999), Senior Grants Manager for the Overseas Program and Special Projects (1999-2006), and Assistant Manager for Program Staff Development (2007-2009). Ford Foundation Office of Management Services staff members like Reis were responsible for grants administration and overseas operations within the foundation's Program Division.
The collection consists of only one series. This series contains office files that Reis created to document his work on several projects at Ford.
Ford Foundation; Program budgeting
- Office files, 1994-2007; 1; 1.14 Cubic Feet About 3 LTR size Hollinger boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Series contains the office files that Kyle Reis created to document his work on several projects related to grants administration and operations support at the Ford Foundation's Office of Management Services and Office of Program Management. These projects include the efforts of the Grant Budgeting and Reporting Taskforce, the implementation of the Vector III recommendations for grant reporting and foundation accountability, and the coordination of the foundation's Program Associates Program.
  Series chiefly consists of correspondence, memos, reports, directory information, notes, surveys, and meeting agendas.
  - Grant Budgeting and Reporting Task Force, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Office of Management Services grant-making overview, 2000-2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vector III - Feedback, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
  - Vector III - Implementation, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  - Vector III - Report drafts, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vector III, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
  - Vector III - Compliance Monitoring Working Group, 1999-2005 (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
  - Fiscal Year 2004-2005 Biennial Worldwide Grant Budget Projections, 1998-2004 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Program Associates Directory updates, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
  - Program Associates Directory updates, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
  - Program Associates Directory updates, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - Program Associates Directory updates, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 24-26)